Kamyab Rouhifar

Web Developer

Email: krouhifar@gmail.com

Phone: 437-984-5385

Address: 19 Copperstone Cres. Richmond Hill, ON L4S 2C5

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kamyab-rouhifar

Website: www.kamyabrouhifar.ca

SUMMARY

The high-performing individual with a proven ability to establish compatible requirements with User Interface Applications. Highly enthusiastic and dependable front-end and back-end web developing professional with more than three years of developing modern web applications using Angular, ReactJS, NodeJS applications.

EDUCATION

Computer Programming and Analysis

Sept 2019 - Present

Seneca College, Toronto

Award:

President's Honor List Fall 2020, President's Honor List Winter 2021,

President's Honor List Fall 2021,

Bachelor of Tech Software Development Scholarship Fall 2019.

- Programmed web development projects using Node.js, React.JS, JavaScript (jQuery), CSS (Bootstrap).
- Installation and setup of Oracle SQL Community servers using C/C++, Java application on Windows/Linux.
- Utilized web applications connected to MongoDB server Database.
- designed data structures, algorithms, and object-oriented programming in the exact specification

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming C/C++, C#, Java, HTML, CSS, JavaScript (jQuery), TypeScript, Python

Database MS SQL, MySQL, Oracle SQL, MongoDB

Bootstrap, Django, NodeJS, ASP.NET MVC, React JS, Angular, React Native Frameworks / Tools **IDE Tools**

MS Office, Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, MS Visual Studio, MS Visual Studio Code

Version Control Git, GitHub, Azure DevOps Server

Case Modeling Visual Paradigm, Draw.io

Cloud Platform Azure Web Apps, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Heroku, Netlify, Google Firebase

Operating System Windows, Linux/Unix

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Server-Side Web applications using Node.js and Express

GitHub: https://github.com/krouhifar/WebServerProject Heroku: https://fast-castle-87951.herokuapp.com/

- Created web pages for administrator, user, and visitor's interface.
- Used HTML 5, CSS3, Vanilla JavaScript, Node.JS, Express and the Handlebars templating engine.
- User data access by MongoDB Database, Google-OAuth 2.0 APIs server.

Web REST API using ReactJS

GitHub: krouhifar/Covid-Tracker (github.com)

Firebase Web Hosting: https://covid19-track.web.app/

- Open-source JavaScript frameworks and libraries (React, jQuery, Bootstraps, GSAP, and Leaflet).
- The concept (application) of front-end web client development for tracking Covid-19.
- A survey of widely-used current front-end development environments.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CAP 2 Associate Sept 2020 – Present

Walmart, Richmond Hill

- Responsible for the processing of orders and shipments according to company policies and procedures.
- Followed company package/shipping standards ensuring all customers received all online order pickups in excellent condition.
- Determined customer needs by asking relevant questions and listening actively to their response.
- Read and comprehend job orders.
- Trained in picking, sorting, packing, and binning.

Full Stack App Developer (Internship)

Jun 2021 - Sept 2021

DoubleClick Lending, Markham

- Researched and built a POC mobile app development by using React Native mobile application.
- Manage application requirement and project coordination through Azure DevOps tools.
- Maintained and administered GIT source code repository through Azure DevOps tools.
- Experienced in working with Angular 10 modules, services, directives, and dependency injection.
- Responsible for creating RESTFUL Web Services to serve data to the front-end application in JSON format.
- Created a custom responsive web application to robust a line-of-business web application using Bootstrap framework.

Activity and Memberships

- Basketball Player.
- CPR and AED First Aid certified.
- Electric Pallet Jack certified.